CONTACT



337-230-5581



lburleigh09@gmail.com



www.betweenthelobes.com



www.linkedin.com/in/lburleigh

EXPERTISE SKILLS

Intelligence Gathering

Data Visualization, + Validation

Instruction + Teaching

Statistics + Machine Learning

Coding Error Resolution

Database Management

Experimental Design

Problem Solving

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Analytical + Critical Thinking

Self-motivated

Adaptable

Prioritization + Planning

Project Management

Communication

Teamwork + Collaboration

Independent Work + Progress

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Gimp Microsoft Office

Google G-Suite NLP

HTML Python

LaTex R

Linux/Bash SPSS

Matlab SOL

LAURYN (L) BURLEIGH PH.D.



ABOUT ME

Expertise in gathering, cleaning, analyzing, and presenting data to technical and non-technical personnel. Advanced understanding of statistical, algebraic, and other analytical techniques. Highly organized, motivated, and diligent with significant background in cognitive and computational neuroscience, collaborated with computer scientists on novel algorithms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Course Instructor - DataCamp

01/2023- Current

Creating an online course for researchers, data scientists, and statisticians to learn A/B test design, data analysis, and data presentation using R.

Graduate Researcher - Louisiana State University

08/2016 - Current

Headed multiple research projects managing 2-8 additional researchers to investigate the acquisition and generalization of fear to visually perceived and mentally imagined stimuli using self-report, skin conductance response, and fMRI measures to further understanding and improve treatment of fear-based mental health disorders such as anxiety and PTSD. Reviewed literature to determine unknown gaps in research, as well as determine and create ideal methodology, statistics including Frequentist, Bayesian, Machine Learning, and Transfer Learning analyses, collect data, and write single and multi-experiment manuscripts for relevant journal publication.

Collaborated as team member of 2-10 researchers on multiple projects investigating fear, mental rotation, working memory, and treat. Provided assistance in methodology creation, instruction on measurement collection, selection and implementation of statistical analyses, and manuscript revision for journal publication.

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Louisiana State University **08/2019 - 12/2022**

Created and instructed labs and lectures, including lab assignments, on understanding and implementing human behavior research statistical analyses using R and SPSS to undergraduate and graduate Psychology students in General Statistics and Intermediate Statistics courses of 15-30 students. Assisted professors in determining lesson plans, course material, course management, homework, and exams, providing suggestion for adapting the courses based on student understanding and progress.

Undergraduate Research Assistant - University of New Orleans

08/2013 - 12/2015

Assisted a team of 5 graduate students gathering, arranging, and maintaining research data collected using self-report, reaction time, salivation, pulse, heart rate and fMRI measures, including creation and coding of automatic calculation data forms and questionnaires and maintaining and calibrating lab equipment for studies investigating stress, cognition, and affective states in special population children with 22q11.2 deletion syndrome.

EDUCATION

M.A., PhD - Louisiana State University

08/2016 - 05/2023

Cognitive and Brain Science

Ph.D. Dissertation - Domain Adaptation in fMRI M.A. Thesis - Neural Mechanisms of Fear

B.S - University of New Orleans **01/2012 - 12/2014**

Psychology Cum Laude